Guide to the David Starr Jordan Papers SC0058
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Letterpress books, 1898-1910; Series I-AA
    - 1905 Mar 4 - Apr 13, 27; 1 volume(s) (Box 13)
    - 1905 Apr 13 - May 15, 28; 1 volume(s) (Box 14)
    - 1905 May 13 - Aug 30, 29; 1 volume(s) (Box 14)
    - 1905 Aug 30 - Oct 14, 30; 1 volume(s) (Box 15)
    - 1905 Oct 14 - Dec 4, 31; 1 volume(s) (Box 15)
    - 1905 Dec 4 - 1906 Jan 15, 1905-1906; 32; 1 volume(s) (Box 16)
    - 1906 Jan 15 - Feb 24, 33; 1 volume(s) (Box 16)
    - 1906 Feb 24 - Apr 17, 34; 1 volume(s) (Box 17)
    - 1906 Apr 17 - May 24, 35; 1 volume(s) (Box 17)
    - 1906 May 24 - Jul 24, 36; 1 volume(s) (Box 18)
    - 1906 Sep 17 - Nov 3, 38; 1 volume(s) (Box 18)
    - 1906 Nov 3 - 1907Jan 8, 1906-1907; 39; 1 volume(s) (Box 19)
    - 1907 Jan 8 - Feb 12, 40; 1 volume(s) (Box 19)
    - 1907 Feb 12 - Mar 18, 41; 1 volume(s) (Box 20)
    - 1907 Mar 18 - May 10, 42; 1 volume(s) (Box 20)
    - 1907 May 9 - Aug 5, 43; 1 volume(s) (Box 21)
    - 1907 Nov 14 - 1908 Jan 13, 1907-1908; 45; 1 volume(s) (Box 21)
    - 1908 Mar 11 - Apr 15, 47; 1 volume(s) (Box 22)
    - 1908 Apr 16 - May 23, 48; 1 volume(s) (Box 22)
    - 1908 May 23 - Aug 29, 49; 1 volume(s) (Box 23)
    - 1908 Aug 29 - Sep 30, 50; 1 volume(s) (Box 23)
    - 1908 Sep 30 - Nov 5, 51; 1 volume(s) (Box 24)
    - 1908 Nov 5 - Dec 19, 52; 1 volume(s) (Box 24)
    - 1908 Dec 19 - 1909 Jan 16, 1908-1909; 53; 1 volume(s) (Box 25)
    - 1909 Jan 16 - Feb 15, 54; 1 volume(s) (Box 25)
    - 1909 Feb 15 - Mar 15, 55; 1 volume(s) (Box 26)
    - 1909 Mar 15 - Apr 13, 56; 1 volume(s) (Box 26)
    - 1909 Apr 13 - May 25, 57; 1 volume(s) (Box 27)
    - 1909 Aug 24 - Sep 30, 60; 1 volume(s) (Box 27)
    - 1909 Sep 29 - Nov 10, 61; 1 volume(s) (Box 28)
    - 1909 Nov 10 - Dec 15, 62; 1 volume(s) (Box 28)
    - 1909 Dec 15 - 1910 Feb 1, 1909-1910; 63; 1 volume(s) (Box 29)
    - 1910 Feb 1 - Mar 14, 64; 1 volume(s) (Box 29)
    - 1910 Mar 14 - Apr 26, 65; 1 volume(s) (Box 30)
    - 1910 Apr 26 - Jun 2, 66; 1 volume(s) (Box 30)
  - Stanford Business Correspondence, 1885-1933; Series I-B
    Scope and content
    Applications for admittance or appointments to Stanford; faculty requests for equipment; salary rolls of the Stanford faculty; University bills; assembly announcements.
    - 1891, January-September (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1891, October-December (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1892, January-August (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1892, September-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1893, January-February (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1893, March-April (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1893, May-June (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1893, July (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1893, August (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1893, September (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1893, October (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1893, November-December (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - 1894, January (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 1894, February-March (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - 1894, April (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - 1894, May-September (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - 1894, October-December (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - 1895, January-May (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - 1895, June-August (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - 1895, September (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - 1895, October-1896, January (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - 1896, February-March (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - 1896, April-October (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - 1896, November-1897, April (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - 1897, May-December (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - 1898, January (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - 1898, February (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - 1898, March (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - 1898, April-May 15 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - 1898, May 16-June (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - 1898, July-August (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - 1898, September (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - 1898, October-November (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - 1898, December-1899, January (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - 1899, February-April (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - 1899, May-June (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - 1899, July (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - 1899, August-September (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - 1899, October (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - 1899, November (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - 1899, December (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - 1899, undated (Box 11, Folder 41a)
    - 1900, January (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - 1900, February (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - 1900, March (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - 1900, April (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - 1900, May (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - 1900, June (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - 1900, July-August (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - 1900, September (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - 1900, October (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - 1900, November (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - 1900, December (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - 1901, January (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - 1901, February (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - 1901, March (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - 1901, April (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - 1901, May 1-15 (Box 16, Folder 57)
    - 1901, May 16-31 (Box 16, Folder 58)
    - 1901, June 1-15 (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - 1901, June 16-30 (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - 1901, July (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - 1901, August (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - 1901, September (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - 1901, October (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - 1901, November (Box 18, Folder 65)
    - 1901, December (Box 18, Folder 66)
    - 1902, January-February (Box 18, Folder 67)
    - 1902, March-April (Box 19, Folder 68)
    - 1902, May-June (Box 19, Folder 69)
    - 1902, July-September (Box 19, Folder 70)
    - 1902, October-December (Box 19, Folder 71)
    - 1903, January (Box 20, Folder 72)
    - 1903, February (Box 20, Folder 73)
    - 1903, March (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - 1903, April (Box 21, Folder 75)
    - 1903 May (Box 21, Folder 76)
    - 1903, June (Box 21, Folder 77)
    - 1903, July (Box 21, Folder 78)
    - 1903, August-September (Box 22, Folder 79)
    - 1903, October (Box 22, Folder 80)
    - 1903, November (Box 22, Folder 81)
    - 1903, December (Box 22, Folder 82)
    - 1904, January (Box 23, Folder 83)
    - 1904, February (Box 23, Folder 84)
    - 1904, March (Box 23, Folder 85)
    - 1904, April (Box 24, Folder 86)
    - 1904, May (Box 24, Folder 87)
    - 1904, June (Box 24, Folder 88)
    - 1904, July (Box 24, Folder 89)
    - 1904, August (Box 25, Folder 90)
    - 1904, September (Box 25, Folder 91)
    - 1904, October (Box 25, Folder 92)
    - 1904, November (Box 25, Folder 93)
    - 1904, December (Box 26, Folder 94)
    - 1905, January-February (Box 26, Folder 95)
    - 1905, March (Box 26, Folder 96)
    - 1905, April (Box 26, Folder 97)
    - 1905, May (Box 27, Folder 98)
    - 1905, June-July (Box 27, Folder 99)
    - 1905, August (Box 27, Folder 100)
    - 1905, September (Box 27, Folder 101)
    - 1905, December (Box 28, Folder 102)
    - 1906, January (Box 28, Folder 103)
    - 1906, February (Box 28, Folder 104)
    - 1906, March (Box 29, Folder 105)
    - 1906, April (Box 29, Folder 106)
    - 1906, May (Box 29, Folder 107)
    - 1906, June (Box 29, Folder 108)
    - 1906, July (Box 30, Folder 109)
    - 1906, August (Box 30, Folder 110)
    - 1906, September (Box 30, Folder 111)
    - 1906, October (Box 30, Folder 112)
    - 1906, November-December (Box 30, Folder 113)
    - 1907, January (Box 31, Folder 114)
    - 1907, February (Box 31, Folder 115)
    - 1907, March (Box 31, Folder 116)
    - 1907, April (Box 31, Folder 117)
    - 1907, May-June (Box 31, Folder 118)
    - 1907, July (Box 32, Folder 119)
    - 1907, August (Box 32, Folder 120)
    - 1907, September (Box 32, Folder 121)
    - 1907, October (Box 32, Folder 122)
    - 1907, November-December (Box 32, Folder 123)
    - 1908, January (Box 33, Folder 124)
    - 1908, February (Box 33, Folder 125)
    - 1908, March (Box 33, Folder 126)
    - 1908, April (Box 33, Folder 127)
    - 1908, May (Box 34, Folder 128)
    - 1908, June (Box 34, Folder 129)
    - 1908, July (Box 34, Folder 130)
    - 1908, August (Box 34, Folder 131)
    - 1908, September (Box 34, Folder 132)
    - 1908, October (Box 35, Folder 133)
    - 1908, November-December (Box 35, Folder 134)
    - 1909, January (Box 35, Folder 135)
    - 1909, February (Box 35, Folder 136)
    - 1909, March (Box 35, Folder 137)
    - 1909, April (Box 36, Folder 138)
    - 1909, May (Box 36, Folder 139)
    - 1909, June-August (Box 36, Folder 140)
    - 1909, September-October (Box 36, Folder 141)
    - 1909, November (Box 36, Folder 142)
    - 1909, December (Box 37, Folder 143)
    - 1910, January-February (Box 37, Folder 144)
    - 1910, March-April (Box 37, Folder 145)
    - 1910, May (Box 37, Folder 146)
    - 1910, June (Box 38, Folder 147)
    - 1910, July (Box 38, Folder 148)
    - 1910, August (Box 38, Folder 149)
    - 1910, September (Box 38, Folder 150)
    - 1910, October (Box 39, Folder 151)
    - 1910, November-December (Box 39, Folder 152)
    - 1911, January (Box 39, Folder 153)
    - 1911, February (Box 39, Folder 154)
    - 1911, March (Box 39, Folder 155)
    - 1911, April (Box 40, Folder 156)
    - 1911, May (Box 40, Folder 157)
    - 1911, June (Box 40, Folder 158)
    - 1911, July (Box 40, Folder 159)
    - 1911, August (Box 41, Folder 160)
    - 1911, September (Box 41, Folder 161)
    - 1911, October (Box 41, Folder 162)
    - 1911, November (Box 41, Folder 163)
    - 1911, December (Box 41, Folder 164)
    - 1912, January (Box 42, Folder 165)
    - 1912, February (Box 42, Folder 166)
    - 1912, March (Box 42, Folder 167)
    - 1912, April (Box 42, Folder 168)
    - 1912, May (Box 42, Folder 169)
    - 1912, June-July (Box 43, Folder 170)
    - 1912, August-September (Box 43, Folder 171)
    - 1912, October (Box 43, Folder 172)
    - 1912, November (Box 43, Folder 173)
    - 1912, December (Box 44, Folder 174)
    - 1913, January (Box 44, Folder 175)
    - 1913, February (Box 44, Folder 176)
    - 1913, March (Box 44, Folder 177)
    - 1913, April (Box 44, Folder 178)
    - 1913, May (Box 45, Folder 179)
    - 1913, June (Box 45, Folder 180)
    - 1913, July-December (Box 45, Folder 181)
    - 1914-1933 (Box 46, Folder 182)
    - Miscellaneous and, undated (Box 46, Folder 183)
    - Miscellaneous and, undated (Box 46, Folder 184)
    - Anderson, Melville B. and the reorganization of the English Department, 1900-01 (Box 47, Folder 185)
    - Barnes, Earl, 1897-1903 (Box 47, Folder 186)
    - Barnett, S.J., resignation (Box 47, Folder 187)
    - Blodgett, Benjamin, circa 1904 (Box 47, Folder 188)
    - Campbell, M.G., 1895 (Box 47, Folder 189)
    - Copeland, E.B., resignation (Box 47, Folder 190)
    - Earle, Homer P., 1902 (Box 47, Folder 191)
    - Fluegel, Ewald and the Carnegie Institution, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 192)
    - Frye, Mrs. Caroline F., DSJ's position on war, 1899: (Box 47, Folder 193)
    - Gilbert, C.H., 1901 (Box 47, Folder 194)
    - Goebel, Julius, original correspondence and documents, 1905 (Box 47, Folder 195)
    - Goebel, Julius, letters and documents, 1904-06 (Box 47, Folder 196)
    - Goebel, Julius, letters and documents, 1904-06 (Box 47, Folder 197)
    - Goebel, Julius, correspondence, 1904-06 (Box 47, Folder 198)
    - Goebel, Julius, correspondence and Advisory Board testimony, 1905 (Box 47, Folder 199)
    - Green, James B., 1892 (Box 48, Folder 200)
    - Professor Green and the haberdasher matter, 1904 (Box 48, Folder 201)
    - Hardy, Irene, Fund, 1905-06 (Box 48, Folder 202)
    - Howard, Burt Estes, 1899-1901 (Box 48, Folder 203)
    - Hussey, J.W. and the Lick Observatory, 1897 (Box 48, Folder 204)
    - Kellogg, V.L., report on woodborers in the arboretum, 1903 (Box 48, Folder 205)
    - McColloch, C.C., student discipline case, 1906-07 (Box 48, Folder 206)
    - MacQueen, Peter (Philippines) (Box 48, Folder 207)
    - Pease, E.M. and Miller, Walter, 1898-1902 (Box 48, Folder 208)
    - Pease, Ernest M. [copies], 1900-02 (Box 48, Folder 209)
    - Ramsey, Marathon, Montrose, drinking problem, 1903 (Box 48, Folder 210)
    - Rolfe, H.W., correspondence re-dismissal copies, 1904-09 (Box 48, Folder 211)
    - Ross, Edward A., correspondence with Jordan, 1893-1900, and undated (Box 48, Folder 212)
    - Ross, Edward A., reactions to his resignation, 1900-01 (Box 48, Folder 213)
    - Ross, Edward A., correspondence regarding, A-C, 1900-01 (Box 48, Folder 214)
    - Ross, Edward A., correspondence regarding, D-F, 1900-01 (Box 49, Folder 215)
    - Ross, Edward A., correspondence regarding, G-L, 1900-01 (Box 49, Folder 216)
    - Ross, Edward A., correspondence regarding, M-S, 1900-01 (Box 49, Folder 217)
    - Ross, Edward A., correspondence regarding, T-Z, 1900-01 (Box 49, Folder 218)
    - Show, A. Barthlow (Box 49, Folder 219)
    - Shults, Dr. J.H., matter: doctor on campus (Box 49, Folder 220)
    - Smith, Mary Roberts, 1901-03 (Box 49, Folder 221)
    - Storey, Thomas A., 1906 (Box 49, Folder 222)
    - Swain, Joseph, Vice-Presidential position, 1895 (Box 49, Folder 223)
    - Thoburn, Wilbur Wilson, death of, 1899 (Box 49, Folder 224)
    - Warner, Amos Griswold, 1903 (Box 49, Folder 225)
    - Wright, Mrs., 1903 (Box 49, Folder 226)
    - Wright, Max G. (Box 49, Folder 227)
    - Cemetery in the arboretum, 1902 (Box 50, Folder 228)
    - Art studio, 1898 (Box 50, Folder 229)
    - Art department, nude model, 1900 (Box 50, Folder 230)
    - Athletic fields, proposed, (includes plans), 1900 (Box 50, Folder 231)
    - Engineering lab, estimate and plans, 1901-02 (Box 50, Folder 232)
    - Faculty housing data, report by J.C. Branner, 1905-06 (Box 50, Folder 233)
    - Hopkins Laboratory, publications, 1895 (Box 50, Folder 234)
    - Hopkins Laboratory, bills and receipts (Box 50, Folder 235)
    - Faculty appointments to the Law School, 1907 (Box 50, Folder 236)
    - Librarian, reports, 1892-93, 1895-96, 1903-04 (Box 50, Folder 237)
    - Librarian, candidates for position, 1906-07 (Box 50, Folder 238)
    - Babine, A.V., Associate Librarian (Box 50, Folder 239)
    - Hildebrand Library, 1895 (Box 50, Folder 240)
    - University Preachers, 1903 (Box 50, Folder 241)
    - Newton, Heber, Chaplain, 1903 (Box 50, Folder 242)
    - Music, School of, rumors concerning, 1902 (Box 50, Folder 243)
    - Pacific Academy (use of the Stanford SF residence as School of History, Economics and Political Science) (Box 50, Folder 244)
    - Stanford University Press, 1903 [1897] (Box 50, Folder 245)
    - Student dormitories, (no correspondence), 1895-1900 (Box 50, Folder 246)
    - Encina Club Room, policy re: use of, 1902 (Box 50, Folder 247)
    - Summer School, committee report, 1903 (Box 50, Folder 248)
    - Westholm: a private home for invalid students, 1903 (Box 50, Folder 249)
    - Accrediting system, esp. Department of Education (Box 51, Folder 250)
    - Addresses at Memorial Service in honor of Librarian Nash and Professor Richardson, 1902-03 (Box 51, Folder 251)
    - Appointments and resignations, 1894 (Box 51, Folder 252)
    - Association of American Universities, Stanford-Berkeley meeting, March 1906 (Box 51, Folder 253)
    - Bonnheim Prize matters, 1906 (Box 51, Folder 254)
    - Correspondence with George A. Clark during DSJ's absences from campus, 1900-06 (Box 51, Folder 255)
    - Colors associated with words or letters, correspondence and research notes., 1892: (Box 51, Folder 256)
    - Crank literature, Shaw's poetry (Box 51, Folder 257)
    - Crank literature, miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 258)
    - Crank literature, miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 259)
    - Crustaceans (Japanese collection): Jordan and Snyder (Box 51, Folder 260)
    - Drainage legislation and Professor Nathan Abbott, 1902 (Box 51, Folder 261)
    - Endowed professorship - Welsh -, 1899 (Box 51, Folder 262)
    - Fish notes from Alan Owston. Yokohama, Japan, 1903 (Box 51, Folder 263)
    - Harkness collection - correspondence, 1901-02 (Box 52, Folder 264)
    - Lathrop, Charles, letters, 1902? (Box 52, Folder 265)
    - Miscellaneous papers - Jordan, 1899-1906 (Box 52, Folder 266)
    - Letters of distinguished men, 1899-1901 (Box 52, Folder 267)
    - Mosquito-feeding fish, 1903-05 (Box 52, Folder 268)
    - Oisson-Seffer, Dehr, report of his visit to La Zacualpa Rubber Plantations, etc, 1905 (Box 52, Folder 269)
    - Properties in the estate of Leland Stanford (Box 52, Folder 270)
    - Rhodes Scholarship matter, 1906-07 (Box 52, Folder 271)
    - Papers relating to Roosevelt's visit, 1903 (Box 52, Folder 272)
    - Dr. Ross and the proposed Palo Alto sanitarium, 1903 (Box 52, Folder 273)
    - Samoa, American - fishes (Box 52, Folder 273a)
    - Spiritualistic origin of the University, DSJ's statement reputing, 1901 (Box 52, Folder 274)
    - Stanford, Jane, reception for given by faculty, 1901 (Box 52, Folder 275)
    - Stanford, Jane to Branner, Stillman, Nash re:increase in their salaries (Box 52, Folder 276)
    - Stanford, Jane, correspondence from DSJ, 1898 and undated (Box 52, Folder 277)
    - Stenographers, 1900-03 (Box 52, Folder 278)
    - Student Guide, report of the, 1903 (Box 52, Folder 279)
    - Taxation, memoranda as to (no author, undated (Box 52, Folder 280)
    - Telephone matters, 1909-10 (Box 52, Folder 281)
    - White, Andrew D., memorandum to the Stanfords, 1892 (Box 52, Folder 282)
    - Leland Stanford, Jr. University, applications received, January 12, 1885-July 24, 1889 (Box 53, Folder 283)
    - Leland Stanford, Jr. University, applications received, July 24, 1889-April 25, 1891 (Box 53, Folder 284)
    - General received, June 8, 1889-September 10, 1891 (Box 54, Folder 285)
    - General received, September 10, 1891-November 5, 1891 (Box 54, Folder 286)
    - President's Office, incoming, A-C, October 1, 1891 (Box 55, Folder 287)
    - President's Office, incoming, D-G, October 1, 1891 (Box 55, Folder 288)
    - President's Office, incoming, H-K, October 1, 1891 (Box 55, Folder 289)
    - University letters, A-C, August 1-30, 1903 (Box 55, Folder 290)
    - University letters, D-J, August 1-30, 1903 (Box 55, Folder 291)
    - University letters, K-Z, August 1-30, 1903 (Box 55, Folder 292)
    - General letters, A-E, August 1-31, 1909 (Box 56, Folder 293)
    - General letters, F-L, August 1-31, 1909 (Box 56, Folder 294)
    - General letters, M-Z, August 1-31, 1909 (Box 56, Folder 295)
    - General letters, A-C, June-July, 1911 (Box 56, Folder 296)
    - General letters, D-H, June-July, 1911 (Box 56, Folder 297)
    - General letters, I-N, June-July, 1911 (Box 56, Folder 298)
    - General letters, O-Z, June-July, 1911 (Box 56, Folder 299)
    - President's Office letters (Box 57, Folder 300)
    - Incoming, A-F, 1891 (Box 58, Folder 301)
    - Incoming, G-Z, 1891 (Box 58, Folder 302)
    - Incoming, A-D, 1892 (Box 58, Folder 303)
    - Incoming, E-M, 1892 (Box 58, Folder 304)
    - Incoming, N-Z, 1892 (Box 58, Folder 305)
    - Incoming, A-M, 1894 (Box 59, Folder 306)
    - Incoming, N-Z, 1894 (Box 59, Folder 307)
    - Incoming, A-Z, 1896 (Box 59, Folder 308)
    - Incoming, A-Z, 1897-1899 (Box 59, Folder 309)
    - Trustees, Crothers, Davis, Leib, 1902-03 (Box 60, Folder 310)
    - Trustees, Crothers, Davis, Leib, Lathrop, 1904 (Box 60, Folder 311)
    - Trustees, Crothers, Davis, 1905 (Box 60, Folder 312)
    - Trustees, Crothers, Davis, 1906 (Box 60, Folder 313)
  - Birthday Wishes, Series I-C
    Scope and Contents
    Birthday wishes addressed to David Starr Jordan. Certain messages from distinguished friends or of merit because of content have been transferred to the General Correspondence file (Series IA).
    - (50th), 1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - (60th), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - (70th), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1923 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous greetings, Undated: (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - (75th), 1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1929 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Telegrams, newspaper clippings, 1930: (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - (80th), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - (80th), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Telegrams, 1931: (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - (80th), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - News articles, 1931: (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Condolences, Series I-D
    Condolences sent to Jessie Knight Jordan at the death of Dr. Jordan. Certain messages from distinguished friends or of merit because of content have been transferred to the General Correspondence file (Series IA).
    - Get Well Wishes. Condolences. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Death: Condolence letters (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Death: Condolence letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Death: Condolence letters from faculty (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Death: Condolence cards (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Death: Telegram condolences (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Death: Miscellaneous - death notices, letters to the University (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Condolences after Eric Knight Jordan's Death (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Condolences: Letters from personal friends (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Condolences: Letters from personal friends and relatives (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Condolences (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Condolences: Letters and telegrams (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Condolences (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tributes after Jordan's Death, Series I-E
    - Tributes (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Tributes (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Tree correspondence, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Tributes, journals (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Tributes, manuscripts (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings collected by the pupils of the Dudley Stone School (Box 2)
    - Series I-AA: Letter books, 1898-1910
      These volumes constitute Jordan's chronological file. Arranged in chronological order by earliest date, each volume contains an alphabetically arranged name index.
      - March 30, 1898 - June 5, 1900 (Box 1, Volume 1)
      - September 27, 1900 - February 5, 1902 and February 1, 1906 - March 12, 1906 (Box 1, Volume 2)
      - November 23, 1900 - May 2, 1901 (Box 2, Volume 3)
      - May 2, 1901 - October 11, 1901 (Box 2, Volume 4)
      - October 9, 1901 - January 4, 1902 (Box 3, Volume 5)
      - January 4, 1902 - February 25, 1902 (Box 3, Volume 6)
      - February 25, 1902 - April 15, 1902 (Box 4, Volume 7)
      - April 15, 1902 - June 11, 1902 (Box 4, Volume 8)
      - June 11, 1902 - September 19, 1902 (Box 5, Volume 9)
      - September 19, 1902 - November 10, 1902 (Box 5, Volume 10)
      - December 24, 1902 - February 6, 1903 (Box 6, Volume 11)
      - February 6, 1903 - March 10, 1903 (Box 6, Volume 12)
      - March 10, 1903 - April 17, 1903 (Box 7, Volume 13)
      - April 17, 1903 - May 20, 1903 (Box 7, Volume 14)
      - May 20, 1903 - June 29, 1903 (Box 8, Volume 15)
      - July 1, 1903 - September 7, 1903 (Box 8, Volume 16)
      - September 7, 1903 - October 27, 1903 (Box 9, Volume 17)
      - October 27, 1903 - December 8, 1903 (Box 9, Volume 18)
      - December 8, 1903 - January 29, 1904 (Box 10, Volume 19)
      - January 28, 1904 - March 7, 1904 (Box 10, Volume 20)
      - March 7, 1904 - June 1, 1904 (Box 11, Volume 21)
      - June 1, 1904 - August 1, 1904 (Box 11, Volume 22)
      - September 25, 1904 - November 2, 1904 (Box 12, Volume 24)
      - December 13, 1904 - January 22, 1905 (Box 12, Volume 25)
      - January 23, 1905 - March 4, 1905 (Box 13, Volume 26)
      - March 4, 1905 - April 13, 1905 (Box 13, Volume 27)
      - April 13, 1905 - May 15, 1905 (Box 14, Volume 28)
      - May 13, 1905 - August 30, 1905 (Box 14, Volume 29)
      - August 30, 1905 - October 14, 1905 (Box 15, Volume 30)
      - October 14, 1905 - December 4, 1905 (Box 15, Volume 31)
      - December 4, 1905 - January 15, 1906 (Box 16, Volume 32)
      - January 15, 1906 - February 24, 1906 (Box 16, Volume 33)
      - February 24, 1906 - April 17, 1906 (Box 17, Volume 34)
      - April 17, 1906 - May 24, 1906 (Box 17, Volume 35)
      - May 24, 1906 - July 24, 1906 (Box 18, Volume 36)